hardwaresphere.com 2013-04-20

# Cookies and Privacy Policy | Hardware Sphere

HardwareSphere.com is committed to protecting your online privacy while providing you with the most useful and enjoyable Web experience possible. While you can use many features of HardwareSphere anonymously, you are required to provide personal information to gain access to some of our premium content and services.

### How we collect and use personal information

Registering for membership on HardwareSphere gives you access to all the site’s information and features. The only information required is your e-mail address, which is primarily used for user authentication. With your approval, we occasionally will send e-mail to notify you about important changes to the site, new services, and special offers from us. If you would rather not receive these e-mail notifications, you can simply indicate that preference either when you register or at any time you modify your account. In addition to receiving e-mail announcements, you can also sign up for daily e-mail newsletter.

If you enter a contest or respond to a promotion, we may ask for your postal address, e-mail address and phone number so we can notify contest winners and deliver promotional goodies.

### Log Files

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocal) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

### Cookies and Web Beacons

We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site. This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as forums.

We also use third party advertisements on HardwareSphere.com to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

You can chose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

### Google and the DoubleClick DART Cookie

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables to serve ads to this site’s visitors based on their visit to this site and other sites on the Internet. Visitors may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

### NetworkAdvertising.org

We also use third-party advertising companies to serve ads from Networkadvertising.org when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

### More about cookies

**Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.**

 **

You can find out more information about advertising cookies and how you can disable them over at the [your online choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/about-behavioural-advertising) website.

**

**You can also change your preferences in your web browser to control cookies for the websites you visit, how this is done varies on your individual browser, please refer to your browser help section for more information on how this can be done.**

Updated on April 2012 to comply with the new UK privacy policies, you can find more details about the new UK and EU cookie law over at the [Information Commissioners Office](http://www.ico.gov.uk/news/blog/2012/updated-ico-advice-guidance-e-privacy-directive-eu-cookie-law.aspx).

### More about our Privacy Policy

We welcomes your questions and comments about our privacy policy. Please send an e-mail to ken[at]hardwaresphere.com and we’ll get back to you as soon as possible.
